inboundmarketing.com 2013-05-29

# Privacy Policy

Last Updated: February 2, 2012

HubSpot is committed to protecting your privacy. This Statement of Privacy applies to the HubSpot website and software platform.  This statement governs the data collection, processing and usage practices of HubSpot. By using the HubSpot website or services platform, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

HubSpot complies with the U.S. E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union and Switzerland respectively. HubSpot has certified that it adheres to the U.S EU and Swiss EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.   Information regarding the both the E.U. and Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks can be found at: <http://export.gov/safeharbor>

## Information Related to Data Collected and Processed for our Clients on our Services Platform

### Service Provider Collection/Use

HubSpot collects information under the direction of its Clients, HubSpot has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. HubSpot works with its Clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected. 

### Choice

We collect information for our clients, if you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly.  If you are a Client and would like to update your account please contact us [here](http://help.hubspot.com/support "here"). 

### Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer

HubSpot may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients

### Access to Data Controlled by our Clients

HubSpot has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the HubSpot Client (the data controller). If the client requests HubSpot to remove the data, HubSpot will respond to their Client's request within 30 business days. 

### Data Retention

HubSpot will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed provide services to our Client. HubSpot will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Open ID 

You can log in to the covered services utilizing sign-in services using an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.

## Website Collection and Use Practices

HubSpot collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, company name, home and/or work address and/or telephone number

In the event that you contact us for customer support through the website, we may also request that you provide additional User Information relevant to the support requested by you. Users are under no obligation to provide such information. However, we cannot guarantee that we can provide customer support in the event that relevant information related to the use of our products or services is withheld. We may retain communications relating to customer support, and/or information drawn from such communications, for statistical and/or reference purposes.

### Social Media (Features) and Widgets: 

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the "Share This" button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

### Links to Other Websites  

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of HubSpot.  If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

### Testimonials

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  

### Public Forums:

Our Web site offers publicly accessible message boards, blogs, and community forums. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through HubSpot public message boards, blogs, or forums, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: HubSpot does not read your private online communications with others.

### Use of your Personal Information

HubSpot collects and uses your personal information to operate the HubSpot website and deliver the services you have requested. HubSpot may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from HubSpot and its affiliates. HubSpot may also contact you via voluntary surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services.  You will always have the option to unsubscribe (see To Unsubscribe From HubSpot below.) HubSpot does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties in which we do not have a formal agreement to provide services to HubSpot and our customers or prospects. HubSpot does not share personally identifiable information except as described in this policy. HubSpot may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, HubSpot may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries or contact you based on your interest to receive such communications. Such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to HubSpot, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.  HubSpot does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

## General Privacy Practices 

## Tracking Technologies

### Log Files

HubSpot also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites using log files

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by HubSpot. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by HubSpot for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the HubSpot website. For these purposes, we do link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information such as name, email address, address, and phone number.

### Cookies

The HubSpot website uses "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web server. Cookies are not used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize HubSpot pages, or register with HubSpot site or services, a cookie helps HubSpot to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same HubSpot website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the HubSpot features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the HubSpot services or websites you visit. HubSpot keeps track of the websites and pages you visit within HubSpot, in order to determine what HubSpot services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within HubSpot to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

### Flash Cookies and Other Third Party Tracking Technologies

The Adobe Flash Player (and similar applications) use technology to remember settings, preferences and usage similar to browser cookies but these are managed through a different interface than the one provided by your web browser. This technology creates locally stored objects that are often referred to as "Flash cookies."

HubSpot does not use Flash cookies.  However, our Clients of our software platform may create pages on the HubSpot platform that employ Adobe Flash cookies.  Our [Terms of Use](http://hubspot.com/terms-of-use "Terms of Use") requires our Clients to inform you about their use of Flash cookies.  HubSpot does not have access or control over our Clients' Flash cookies, but you may access your Flash management tools from Adobe's web site directly.  

Similarly, our Clients may create pages on the HubSpot platform that use technology from tracking utility companies, such as cookies and web beacons   The use of these technologies by our Clients is not covered by our privacy statement.  We do not have access or control over these third party tracking technologies.

### Advertising 

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites.  Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here <http://preferences.truste.com/>. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads. 

### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ [or our third party advertising partner employs] a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie [do not tie] the information gathered by clear gifs to our customer's personally identifiable information.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients.  This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.  If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see Choice and Opt-out. 

**Third Party Tracking Technologies**

The use of cookies and web beacons by any tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy statement.  We do not have access or control over these third party tracking technologies. 

### Legal Disclaimer

HubSpot websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on HubSpot or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of HubSpot (including enforcing this agreement); and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of HubSpot, or the public.

### Access to Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, request deletion on our site by emailing us at [privacy@hubspot.com](mailto:privacy@hubspot.com) to our Privacy team.  We will respond to all access requests within 30 days. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

If you request that your user information be deleted from our records, there may be a brief delay in our processing that request, while verify that the request is valid and originates from you as opposed to an unauthorized third party. If you request that your information be deleted, we reserve the right to terminate and/or limit your access to the HubSpot website.

If you provide HubSpot with user information, you have the following rights with respect to that information:

  * To review the user information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that we correct any errors, outdated information, or omissions in user information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that your user information not be used to contact you
  * To request that your user information be removed from any solicitation list that we use
  * To request that your user information be deleted from our records and
  * To opt out of being solicited by this website or third parties

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at [privacy@hubspot.com](mailto:privacy@hubspot.com).

### Security of your Personal Information

No method of safeguarding information is 100% secure. HubSpot uses a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. HubSpot secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When sensitive personal information (such as a credit card number) is collected on our site and/or transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@hubspot.com](mailto:privacy@hubspot.com).  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Changes to this Statement

HubSpot will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. HubSpot encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how HubSpot is protecting your information. When such a change is made, we will update the "Last Updated" date above. **** If we make any material changes we will notify you or our Client by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### To Unsubscribe From HubSpot

You may unsubscribe from HubSpot marketing communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of the company's emails. Additionally, you may unsubscribe by contacting HubSpot Support at 1-888-HUBSPOT (1-888-482-7768) extension 3.   

HubSpot's customers may send emails from our platform with HubSpot's logo to show our tools capabilities however HubSpot does not control the email addresses directly and therefore cannot unsubscribe you from our customers' emails on your behalf.  Please contact the sender of that email which will include proper unsubscribe links if sent via our product. 

### Contact Information

HubSpot welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that HubSpot has not adhered to this Statement, please contact HubSpot at [privacy@hubspot.com](mailto:privacy@hubspot.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. HubSpot is located at 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141.  We can be reached by phone at 1-888-HUBSPOT (1-888-482-7768).

## TRUSTe Privacy Seal

HubSpot, Inc. ("HubSpot") has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's [Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/program_requirements_website_privacy.html) and the [TRUSTe Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/trusted-cloud/index.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's certification applies to the website located at [www.hubspot.com](http://www.hubspot.com/) and the services platform reached by logging in at <https://login.hubspot.com/login> and residing on the HubSpot domain. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at privacy@hubspot.com.  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).
